Guide to the Church Women United in the Schenectady Area records, 1935-2016
Church Women United in the Schenectady Area records, 1935-2016
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Church Women United in the Schenectady Area records, 1935-2016.
3430
Church Women United in the Schenectady Area (N.Y.)
2.3 cubic ft.
Constitutions, minutes of and agenda for meetings, correspondence and memoranda, clippings and programs, schedules of events, rosters, attendance sheets, reports, budget proposals, financial records, photographs, newsletters, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Contains organizational records, including material related to affiliation and cooperation with local, national, and international organizations and records of predecessor organizations.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes constitutions, minutes of and agenda for meetings, correspondence and memoranda, clippings and programs, and yearly schedules of events; rosters of officers, members, and committee chairmen; attendance sheets; president's and secretary's annual reports, reports of the nominating and executive committees and committees in charge of arranging for such celebrations and observances as May Fellowship Day, World Community Day, and World Day of Prayer; treasurer's reports, budget proposals, and other financial records; and group photographs, programs, biographical data on speakers, newsletters, and miscellaneous items having to do with the aims and activities of the organization. Also, mimeographed and printed material with relevant correspondence and notes concerning its affiliation or cooperation with local, national, and international organizations devoted to the betterment of mankind, among them the American Host Program, Charlton School (Saratoga County), Church Women United in New York State, Church World Service, Committee of Clergy and Laymen Concerned about Viet Nam, Cooperative Extension of Schenectady County, Environmental Clearinghouse of Schenectady, Family Court (New York State), League of Women Voters, Literacy Volunteers, Inc. (Syracuse), National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, National Council for Church Women (later CWU), National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A., New York State Council of Churches, Red Cross, Schenectady Area Peace Center, Schenectady Area Council of Churches, Volunteer Bureau of the Community Welfare Council of Schenectady County, Women in Community Service (Washington), and the United Nations. Also included are similar records of predecessor organizations, the Women's Missionary Federation of Schenectady (1935- ), and the Schenectady Council of Church Women (1948-1957), and incomplete runs of the annual reports (1956/1957, 1971/1972) of Church Women United in New York State and its quarterly, Together (1967-1972).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Church Women United in the Schenectady Area (N.Y.); American Host Program.; American Red Cross.; Charlton School (N.Y.); Church Women United in New York State.; Clergy and Laymen Concerned About Vietnam (U.S.); Cooperative Extension Association of Schenectady County (N.Y.); Environmental Clearinghouse of Schenectady.; League of Women Voters (U.S.); Literacy Volunteers of Syracuse (N.Y.); National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (U.S.); National Council of Church Women.; National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America.Church World Service; New York (State).Family Court.; New York State Council of Churches.; Schenectady Area Council of Churches (N.Y.); Schenectady Area Peace Center (N.Y.); Schenectady Council of Church Women (N.Y.); Schenectady County (N.Y.).Community Welfare Council.Volunteer Bureau.; United Nations.; Women in Community Service (U.S.); Women's Missionary Federation of Schenectady (N.Y.)
Titles:
Together.
Subjects:
Women and religion--New York (State)--Schenectady.; Women--Societies and clubs--New York (State)--Schenectady.; Religious institutions--New York (State)--Schenectady.
Places:
Schenectady (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Constitutions.; Minutes.; Reports.; Newsletters.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- State CWU: President's reports and state information, 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Publicity and historiae, 1969, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Programs: CWU, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Human Rights, Ca. 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- CWU programs and publicity, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Legislative information, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- National CWU Urban Program, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Public relations planning packet, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Public relations planning packet, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- CWU programs and reports, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Church World Service: CROP and Clothing Appeal, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- CWU members and miscellaneous, 1959-1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Councilor articles newsletters, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Environmental Clearinghouse News, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Coffee hours, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Regional meeting, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Women in a Changing World, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Old agendas and work sheets, 1970, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Probation services, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Draft exiles, 1971, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Annual meetings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- World Day of Prayer, 1951-1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- "Together" CWU publications, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- National CWU--correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- The Charleton School, 1971, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous items, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- American Host program, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Schenectady Area Council of Churches, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- May Fellowship Day, 1949-1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Table Talks on world affairs, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Peoples Rights, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Celebrations: World Community Day, etc., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Council of Churches Board Meetings, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Citizens Convention for the Schenectady Schools, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Attendance sheets, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- WICS: Women in Community Service, Inc., 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- CWU agenda and work sheets, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Churches of Meetings of Councils, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Communications, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Cooperative Extension, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- International Development, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 41)
- The Fellowship, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Literacy Volunteers, Inc., 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Local agencies, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Migrants: Migrant Ministry, 1969, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Mission Study, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Other programs, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Race relations, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- School Lunch Program, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Speakers Bureau, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- United Nations, 1964-1965, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Viet Nam, 1966-1967, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Women in Community Service, Ind., 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- World Community Day, 1959-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Nominating Committee: ideas adopted, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Legislation, 1963, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence to and from the President Blanche R. Kelly, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Church Women United Annual Reports, 1948-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Annual Meetings, 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Publicity, etc: clippings discarded, 1934-1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Executive Commitee, 1961-1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Coffee Hours, 1960-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- CWU general information, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Membership lists, 1961, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Constitution, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Treasurer's reports, 1962-1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- President's notebook, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Programs, meetings, agendas, and miscellaneous information, 1961-1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Programs, meetings, agendas, and miscellaneous information, 1961-1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- State Council Annual, NYS Council of Churches, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- New Dimensions in a Continuing Commitment, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Handbook for United Church Women (Box 2)
- Annual Reports, 1956-1972 (Box 2)
- Clippings and programs, 1980-1996 (Box 3)
- Annual reports, newsletters, and publicity material, 1984-1996 (Box 3)
- Annual reports, newsletters, programs and publicity material, 1997-2011 (Box 4, Folder 1-6)
- Materials relating to activities of the CWU in Schenectady, NY, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 7)